Madeleine Kemeny

Design Professional ms-madeleine.net ms.madeleine@att.net 773-510-8033

Summary

I am an experienced graphic designer and project manager, with a strong background in branded communications. I have engaged in both corporate and nonprofit sector projects at all levels, from strategy development to end-user deliverable.

I took a brief sabbatical from Graphic Design to explore the Restaurant & Hospitality Industry, and I rose to the level of senior management as Pastry Chef. Along the way, I discovered that Food and Design are mostly the same thing... but one tastes better. And as much fun as Fine Dining is, it is inaccessible to most people.

I want to return to Design and find meaningful, challenging, and accessible work: as entertainment, education, cultural enrichment, technology, and the most basic pieces of visual communication.

Work Experience:

Self-employed, 7/1996 - Present

Clients have included: Curt's Cafe, Morgan Cohen, The Axelson Center for Nonprofit Management -North Park University, CloudCheckr, Inc., Range, Inc., Abbell Credit Corporation, IGK Galleries, Mind 2 Body Studio, Jewish Reconstructionist Congregation, National Center for Higher Education Risk Management, Children's Memorial Hospital, Alzheimer's Association Greater Illinois Chapter, Arthritis Foundation - Greater Chicago Chapter, Chicago Tribune Charities, Metropolitan Family Services, International Society for the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect, The Nature Conservancy, Audubon - Chicago Region, Sahm Acupuncture, Scleroderma Foundation, University of Chicago Medical Center, Women's Self Employment Project / WSEP Ventures, Alternatives, Inc., The Better Boys Foundation, Student Sponsorship Programme / Umfundaze, Social Capital Partnerships / Special Olympics, Public / Private Ventures, The Society for Marketing Professional Services-Chicago Chapter, Women in Direct Marketing International–Chicago Chapter, St. Peter's Church in the Loop, Ancient Biblical Manuscript Center, Beth Emet: The Free Synagogue, Old St. Patrick's Church, Hales Franciscan High School, The Frederik Meijer Gardens & Sculpture Park, Illinois Road and Transportation Builders Association, Rider Dickerson, Inc., K-Five Construction Corporation, Western Remac Inc., Smith Design Co., LoSasso Advertising, CLA Communications, Chandlergroup, Eva Maddox Associates, Kate Friedman Design, The Millenson Collaborative, IDIA, Concrete, The Grillo Group, Gerhardt & Clemons, Hartford Design, Olver Dunlop Associates, Performance Direct, HOK, Inc., RTKL Associates, Inc., Deloitte Tax Technology Group, Circurio / ReAl LLC, Cityscape / Higher Gear Road Racing Team, Appellate Court Justice Joy V. Cunningham, and Hubert Law Group.

Pastry Chef, Found Kitchen & Social House and The Barn, 7/2016 – 10/2016

Performed all duties as Pastry Chef for Found while concurrently working as Pastry Chef for a new restaurant, The Barn (opened November 2016).

MADELEINE KEMENY :: MS.MADELEINE@ATT.NET PAGE 1 OF 4

Oversaw AM prep kitchen and managed operations with Chef de Cuisine: staffing, schedules, budgets, labor reports, inventory, work-flow, sanitation compliance, product R & D, staff training.

Ran out-of-house events, including Shine & Dine for Step Up (800 guests), Guest Chef Series at Chicago Botanic Gardens (150 guests in two presentations), and Feast at the Farm with Temperance Beer Company, Hewn, and Hazzard Free Farm (75 guests).

Collaborated with Beverage Director and bar staff.

Pastry Cook, Perennial Virant (Lincoln Hotel, Joie de Vivre Group), 2/2016 - 6/2016

Produced breads, pastries, desserts, and bakery items for use in the multiple outlets of this former BOKA Group entity in Lincoln Park.

Lead-baker/oversaw AM prep kitchen shift.

Pastry Cook, Spiaggia, 11/2015 - 2/2016

Produced components for and plated for service the dessert menu at this Michelin-starred restaurant.

Chef, Smack Dab, 8/2015 - 10/2015

Consulted on overall development and growth of this pop-up concept (now permanent storefront), including: developing recipes, producing daily menu, training staff and owners, negotiating operating agreements, developing expansion plans, and conducting feasibility studies.

Pastry Cook, Found, 7/2014 - 8/2015

Worked directly with Executive Chef Nicole Pederson to create seasonal dessert items congruent to scope of both lunch and dinner menus.

Expanded recipe archive.

Created custom recipes for cookies, cakes, jams, sauces, and custards.

Supported Savory Prep with pickle recipes.

Assisted with plating for parties and special events.

Demo Specialist, Whole Foods Market, 11/2013 - 7/2014

Recipe development and live demos of cooking techniques and serving suggestions/product usage. Customer service and interaction regarding highlighted products, menu ideas, flavors, food purchases, store policies, and general information.

Classroom format cooking lessons for private groups.

Recipe writing and presentation concept development in conjunction with store marketer.

Baker, Pie and Coffee/Hoosier Mama Pie Company, 11/2013 - 7/2014

Produced recipes for pies, scones, muffins, doughs, and biscuits.

Other duties included recipe development for new muffins and cakes, training of new staff, collaborations with Savory team on sandwich, soup, and side recipes.

MADELEINE KEMENY :: MS.MADELEINE@ATT.NET

Director of Design, Take Me to GCloud, 11/2012 – 7/2013

Developed branding for Google Apps reseller and clientele.

Senior Graphic Designer, Eva Maddox Associates, 7/2001 – 4/2002

Clients included: American Federation of Teachers, Oak Park Public Library, La Petite Academy, Bolta/MDC Wallcoverings, The Cove School

Senior Designer, Ovresat Paredes Design, 9/1998 – 10/1999

Clients included: The Chicago Academy for the Arts, Child's Voice, Harcourt Brace, Rigby Publishing, and Scott Foresman.

Designer, Brainforest, Inc., 9/1997 - 9/1998

Clients included: American Economic Development Corporation, Crain's Chicago Business, Hyundai Construction Equipment, Jam Productions, The Lookingglass Theatre, Motorola, Museum of Science and Industry, National Alzheimer's Association, and The National Restaurant Association.

Designer, Lipman Hearne, 5/1995 – 8/1996

Clients included: Chapin Hall Center for Children, Chicago Symphony Orchestra, Ford Foundation, Jewish United Fund, The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Metropolitan Family Services, National Society of Fundraising Executives, The Smithsonian Institution, and University of Chicago Laboratory Schools.

Designer, Art Researcher, & Art Buyer, Ligature Creative Studios 9/1994 – 5/1995 Client: Silver Burdett Ginn.

Volunteer Experience

- Chicago Waldorf School, 2011 2015: Holiday Fair and class trips
- Benefit Committee Co-chair for Alternatives, Inc., 1997 2009
- RISD Alumni Club Coordinator, 1994 2000

Languages

- French (proficient)
- Spanish (rusty but improves with practice)

Education

- Rhode Island School of Design, BFA, Graphic Design, 1990 1994
- Northwestern University, Certificate (anticipated 10/2019); current GPA: 4.0) Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp, 2019

PAGE 3 OF 4

MADELEINE KEMENY :: MS.MADELEINE@ATT.NET

 $\frac{\textbf{Interests}}{\textbf{Cooking, food justice, sustainable agriculture, pickling \& preserving, gardening}}$

Honors and Awards

Cochon 555 Chicago April 2015 Competition Winner — team of Chef Nicole Pederson NeoCon Gold - Haworth Showroom, 1997, The Merchandise Mart

Certifications

Servsafe/Illinois Restaurant Association, Manager-level certification.

MADELEINE KEMENY :: MS.MADELEINE@ATT.NET PAGE 4 OF 4